Curriculum Vitae



Fangming Du

Senior Architect

Fangming is a Singapore and Austria trained architect. He has been involved in a wide continuum of architectural projects comprising transportation, master planning, retail, residential, institutional and commercial buildings. He holds a Master's Degree from University of Singapore, and he is a Registered Architect in Singapore.

Fangming has led and assisted the design coordination and project administration in some of the largest scale transportation and mixed development projects in Singapore, and he was also the representative Head of Computation Design (Rhino & Revit) in Hassell Singapore studio, managing the digital aspects of the design and documenting process in the office.

Fangming has acquired a vast experience working and documenting with multiple digital design platforms, including Rhino (Grasshopper, Vray etc.), Revit and other related BIM software. He has since demonstrated a great passion and knowledge in multi- discipline design with emerging technologies.

His key projects include the World's first 4-in-1 east coast depot comprising office, administration building and depots; as a leading architect, he has went through preliminary design, tender and construction stage as well as preparing authority submissions and dealing with compliance requirement.

For the past two years, as the Senior Architect of MKPL, his main scope is

managing the award winning project: Bidadari Alkaff Courtview and Lakeview which consists of 1,789 units with mixed commercial and educational development, in which the masterplan of the Bidadari Estate is also designed by the same office. Currently his role is contract administration, BIM and project management. He liaises and coordinates with external consultants and clients on a daily basis as well as managing on-site matters.

Qualification

- Registered Architect, Board of Architect No. 2813
- Master of Architecture, National University of Singapore, 2014
- Bachelor of Arts (Architecture), National University of Singapore, 2012
- Bachelor of Science (Architecture), Exchange Program scholarship, Innsbruck Universität, Austria, 2011

Professional Experience <u>Singapore</u>

2017-Present MKPL Architects <u>Singapre</u>

2014-2017 HASSELL Design

_ 2011-2012 Coop Himmelb(l)au Austria

Project Experience

Residential and Commercial Bidadari Alkaff courtview and Alkaff

lakeview, Singapore (Innovation Award), Singapore

Jalan Besar / Rochor Central Residential with Commercial C7 & C8. Singapore

_ One Holland Village, Singapore

Transportation and Workplace

_ Thomson East Coast Line, Contract

E1001, Singapore

_ World's first 4-in-1 Mega Depot comprising Downtown Line Depot (DTL), Eastern Region Line Depot (TEL), East West Line Depot (EWL), Thomson East Coast Line Mega Multi-story Bus Depot and Office Development, Singapore

TE31 Sungei Bedok underground Station, Singapore

- DT36 Xilin underground Station, Singapore
- _ ER481 Bus Depots, Singapore

Competition and Tender Bidding

One Holland Village, Singapore (Success)

Esplanade extension Waterfront Theatre, Singapore (Unbuilt)

Outward Bound Singapore at Coney Island masterplan and development, Singapore (Unbuilt)

Jurong Region Line MRTs, Singapore (Success)

Jurong Region Line Depots, Singapore (Success)

Specialist Expertise

- BIM Modelling and Management
- Computational Design
- Architectural Simulation & Analysis
- Augmented Reality (AR) Modelling
- Project Management and Client Engagement

Professional Skills

- Revit (BIM), Rhino 3D (Grasshopper, V-ray, parametric design), CAD and Sketchup
- Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office

BIM Coordination and Documentation, Perspective Rendering

Design Simulation & Animation (Ecotect, Grasshopper, Processing)

Design Coordination and Contract Administration

Pre-work Achievement

- 2003-2008 Singapore Government Scholarship holder
- Project Advisor, Community Built Project in China 2013
- Competition / Designer, NUS Student Lounge + Studio Competition
- Exhibition / Designer, NUS Department of Architecture 50th Anniversary

Language Proficiency

- Spoken/Written English
- Spoken/Written Chinese
- Spoken/Written German (Intermediate level equivalent B2)
- Spoken/Written Japanese (Simple)

Email: fm@creaturexd.com Phone: +65-96806048, Singapore

Portfolio: pdf.creaturexd.com Simulation Researches: vimeo.com/ bfcxfm